So let's go and practice the SQS service.
So in SQS we see it's a message queuing service
and the idea is that we have a high-throughput
system-to-system messaging service.
So we're going to go ahead and create a queue,
which is going to be free.
So as you can see, we have two types of queue
we can create, a standard queue or a FIFO queue.
Now this is way beyond the scope of the exam
for the Cloud Practitioner.
So I'm just going to do standard
and I will call my queue demo-sqs.
In terms of the configuration, you can safely don't look
at all these things, again, it's more advanced
than we need to know as well as the access policy,
we can leave everything as default.
So what I'll just do is create the queue.
Now my queue is created, and we can start sending
and receiving messages from it.
So let me close these panels right here.
So we have all the configuration panels here, but again,
not in this scope, so let's not do,
deal with them right now,
but here we have our queue details where we can find
the type of queue it is, the name,
whether or not we enable encryption and so on.
And we if we click on more,
we get some more information and we get some information
around how many messages are available,
how many messages are in flight,
how many messages are delayed?
So what we're going do is to produce and consume permits.
So for it we'll go on the top right hand side
and there is send and receive messages.
So once I click on send and receive messages,
you can send a message
so we'll send the message, hello world.
And then we can just click on send message.
Now as you can see, the message has been sent
and it's ready to be delivered,
received and if you click on view details,
you can get some information around that message,
so the message ID as well as the MD5 attributes,
but more importantly, if we scroll down,
we can see that now in the receive message section,
one message is available.
So if I just do another one, so I say another hello
and press send message, now you see that
the messages available is two.
So now we need to poll the queue to receive these messages.
So click on poll for messages,
and this will go ahead and retrieve these messages for me.
As we can see, the two messages here are showing up
and on application, we click on them,
we'd actually read them, so look at the body and say,
okay, this looks like hello world,
which is the exact message I sent.
We could look at some attributes and so on.
If there were say, if there were some sets,
but what the application will do is that it will read
the messages and this is the application you would have
to code obviously and then when the message processing
is done, you would click on the messages
and then delete them to remove them from the queue
and as you can see, messages available is zero.
Very, very simple, but that's how SQS works at a high level.
Now, if you go back to your queues,
you will get a list of all your queues
and to finish this hands on, you can go ahead
and delete this queue.
This won't cost you any money, but it's not bad
to clean up after yourself.
So that's it.
We should enter the word delete, sorry.
So that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.